Guide to the R. Emms Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
R. Emms papers
1900-1903
MS 1815
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
The papers consist of diaries, memorabilia, printed materials, and photographs of R. Emms, a noncommissioned officer in the British Army, Company E, 2nd Batallion, Norfolk Regiment, during the Boer War in South Africa. In his diaries and sketches, Emms recounts army life and battles in which he participated. The photographs are primarily of the Norfolk Regiment encampment and soldiers.
Emms, R.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator, 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of diaries, memorabilia, printed materials, and photographs of R. Emms, a noncommissioned officer in the British Army, Company E, 2nd Batallion, Norfolk Regiment, during the Boer War in South Africa. In his diaries and sketches, Emms recounts army life and battles in which he participated. The photographs are primarily of the Norfolk Regiment encampment and soldiers.
South African War, 1899-1902 -- Personal narratives; South African War, 1899-1902; South Africa -- History -- 1836-1909; Emms, R.
- Inventory
  - Diaries [two], 1900-1902 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Medals [with attached ribbons], 1901, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Messages [handwritten; signed D. M. D. L.], 1900 December 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Pouch [handmade], [1900?] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Printed material
    - Employment identity card, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Scripture Union brochure, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Soldier's New Testament, South Africa 1900" (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sports programme, 1902 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sketch of battlefield [on verso of postal money order addressed to Thomas Emms], 1902 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs
    - Norfolk Regiment soldiers, encampment, natives, [1900-1902] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Portrait [of an unidentified man and woman], undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Oversize [special Transvaal edition of The Bloemfontein Post; "Diary of the War," unidentified newspaper, 1901 February 7, undated (Box 2)